Andre De Coppet Collection, 1566-1936 (bulk 1770-1865 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- United States. Army of the Potomac, 1862; 2 boxes
  - Correspondence, 1862 April-December; 4 folders
    - Suydam, C.C., 1862 July 6-December 25; 1 folder
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 August 9; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From J. J. Abercrombie. Forwarding a nominal list of officers of the regular army serving with his command. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 August 10; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Nicholas W. Day. Forwarding the names of officers from General Couch's division for the ambulance corps. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 August 13; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Robert M. West. Reporting that a portion of the meat ration for his command is unfit for consumption. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 August 20; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Robert M. West. Requesting that in the event of a march to Fortress Monroe, the artillery be allowed to move in the advance. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 August 21; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Charles E. Pease. Requesting aid for the sick left at Yorktown and a guard for the public stores. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 August 22; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Dan Lodor. Concerning passes to visit Fort Monroe. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 August 28; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Wilson Barstow. Requesting lists of divisions, brigades, and regiments of the 4th corps to assist in forwarding stragglers. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 August 31; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From T. G. Orwig. Submitting a report of the condition of his battery at the time of muster. 2 pp. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 1; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Lt. Howard. A telegram regarding an unnamed general. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 1; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From George Clark. Requesting a man be detailed as soon as possible. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 4; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Henry M. Hoyt. Requesting to be relieved as provost marshal of the 4th corps. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 4; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From J. P. Wilson. Telegram reporting that three men who took Mr. Sweeney's horse were acting under orders. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 8; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Henry M. Hoyt. Stating the instructions he gave to his sergeant regarding the mail boat. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 9; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From J. P. Wilson. Asking if he can use recruits to fill the spots of 50 men who have reported absent or sick and have not been discharged or deserted. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 13; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Cadwallader. Reporting that the trial nurses have all proved themselves to be fit for the job and should be regularly detailed. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 13; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Andrew Fagan. Reporting that James Bambrick, a deserter, is requesting to be restored to duty. 2 pp. with docketing plus another small slip of paper.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 13; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Floyd Clarkson. Reporting that General Dix cannot give him a leave of absence and he therefore must ask for a resignation as there is no place for him and other officers to sleep at Fort Monroe. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 13; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Floyd Clarkson. Tendering his resignation. 2 pp.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 14; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Joshua Norton, Jr. Requesting the position of post sutler at Yorktown. Sending recommendations signed by commissioned officers. 1 p. with four enclosed recommendation letters.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 14; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From G.B. Dandy. Suggesting two men who were serving with the quartermaster department on extra duty be ordered to rejoin their companies. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 15; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From Henry M. Hoyt. Relating to the sale of goods from vessels. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 21; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From A. Faith. Reporting that he has taken command of the 5th Pennsylvania Cavalry. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 22; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From John Carter Brown. Asking for action against Ferdinand Levy, who has resigned but refuses to hand over the muster roll of his company. 2 pp. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 24; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From David Bower. Reporting the condition of the Williamsburg sawmill and the repairs needed to get it in working order. With an estimate of the cost of materials and work. 2 pp. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 October 25; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From W.G. McCandless. Forwarding discharges and reminding Suydam that there are others to which he should attend. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 November 29; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From J.J. DeForest. Reporting that artillery practice earlier in the day came close to hurting some soldiers chopping wood. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 December 16; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From D.T. Van Buren. Relating to his monthly report. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 December 17; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From William Lewis. Requesting that a number of unserviceable horses be replaced. 1 p with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 December 20; 1 item (Folder 3)
        Forwarded by J.G. Farnsworth. Describing a horse and reporting its value. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 December 24; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From John Nicholson. Asking that two of his men serving with the provost guard be returned. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 December 24; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From H. M. Plaisted. Requesting that five of his men detached to Fitch's battery be returned to their regiment. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 December 24; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From William Lewis. Requesting that new recruits be collected and transported to his regiment. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Suydam, C.C., 1862 December 25; 1 item (Folder 3)
        From M.G. Cushing. Forwarding an application for a furlough for Louis Wunch. 1 p. with docketing.
    - Williams, Seth, 1862 June-August; 1 folder
      Letters addressed to the Assistant Adjutant General reporting news and requesting certain military actions. 5 items.
      - Williams, Seth, 1862 July 7; 1 item (Folder 4)
        From J.S. Belknap. Recommending some promotions. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Williams, Seth, 1862 July 9; 1 item (Folder 4)
        From John J. Peck. Requesting that a regular battery be assigned to his command. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Williams, Seth, 1862 July 15; 1 item (Folder 4)
        From A.T. Watson. Reporting the death of captain George T. Lewis. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Williams, Seth, 1862 August 5; 1 item (Folder 4)
        From Seth Williams. Forwarding a letter regarding digging wells and procuring water for the troops. 3 pp. with docketing.
      - Williams, Seth, 1862 August 11; 1 item (Folder 4)
        From E.D. Keyes. Requesting that an additional squadron of cavalry be assigned to the 4th corps. 1 p. with docketing.
    - Miscellaneous, 1862 April-December; 1 folder
      Letters to and from military officers of varying ranks.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 April 22; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Seth Williams to the Office of the Provost Marshall. Ordering the Commissary of Subsistence at Ship Point to issue rations to the family of John R. Walter. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 July 26; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From W.A. Emory to Captain Morris. Recommending Captain Dandy be appointed a colonel. With a note from John J. Peck on the back. 2 pp.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 August 9; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From a colonel [illegible] to General Howe. Providing names for a detail. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 August 11; 1 item (Folder 5)
        Bill/receipt from William Laverey to the U.S. Government for 125 bushels of wheat. 1 p.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 August 22; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From H.A. Walker to Oswald Jackson. Reporting that no one from the 1st division has visited Fortress Monroe on any pass or order from the commanding officer. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 August 23; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Charles E. Pease to Oswald Jackson. Reporting that the 5th Pennsylvania Cavalry is not under the command of General Van Allen. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 August 28; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From B.B. Foster to Captain Jackson. Sending a query from General Peck as to who will continue work on the fortifications now that General Couch's working party has been withdrawn. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 August 29; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From W.A. Emory to Foster. Requesting that the soon to be disbanded 8th N.Y. Militia hand over their arms and accoutrements to a group of newly arrived recruits. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 August 29; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Charles E. Pease to Oswald Jackson. Requesting an order detailing fifty men for Post Guard. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 August 29; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From J.G. Farnsworth to Oswald Jackson. Requesting officers and men to form a guard for the wagon train at headquarters. 1 p.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 6; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From David Bower to General Haglee. Concerning the issuing of a receipt to Mr. Lavery for wheat he provided. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 September 15; 1 item (Folder 5)
        Printed form letter from James W. Ripley of the Ordnance Office to the commanding officer of the works at Yorktown, VA. Requesting an inventory of all the ordnance and ordnance stores at Yorktown. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 3; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From E.P.M. Kinney to John A. Dix. Reporting the murder of Captain D.C. Hannahs. 2 pp.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 8; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From William P. Hall to an unknown major. Enclosing passes for a Mrs. Newman, reporting that people are daily leaving Williamsburg for Richmond. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 13; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Phineas Stanton to Captain George H. Johnston. Reporting progress on the works at Gloucester Point. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 13; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From W. Kreutzer to Captain George H. Johnston. Requesting that Colonel Durkee, Lt. Colonel Weed, and Major Clarke be ordered before a military commission as he believes they are unfit to hold their present positions. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 13; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From W.W.H. Davis to George H. Johnston. Requesting that his quartermaster be ordered to Alexandria to bring recruits, convalescents, and rifles. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 14; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Riley Johnson to an unnamed general. Requesting that his company blacksmith, currently in the service of Major Floyd Clarkson, be ordered back to his company. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 20; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From L. Thomas to John A. Dix. Relating to extra commissioned and non-commissioned officers of batteries. 2 pp.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 23; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Floyd Clarkson to Captain Jackson. Saying he cannot spare his blacksmith. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 October 24; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Charles Durkee to George H. Johnston. Requesting that a board of survey be appointed to inspect his regiment's tents, as he believes they are unfit for winter use. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 December 15; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Samuel G. Sewall to George H. Johnston. Reporting the numbers of cattle, sheep and horses captured for the U.S. Army from persons residing in the vicinity of Gloucester House, VA. 3 pp. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 December 16; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Leonard F. Hepburn to Henry W. Benson. Notifying Benson that he must report to General Davis at Fort Monroe. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 December 19; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From J.T. Seawell to Colonel Davis. Asking for information in regard to purchasing back his two horses. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 December 24; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Henry C. Knoop to D.T. Van Buren. Requesting that Monroe T. Bennett be ordered to join his corps. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 December 24; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From C. N. Otis to George H. Johnston. Reporting that an attack is to be made on Gloucester Point tonight. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, 1862 December 25; 1 item (Folder 5)
        From Charles Durkee to George H. Johnston. Requesting that all men belonging to his command on detached service at Yorktown be returned to his regiment. 1 p. with docketing.
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 item (Folder 5)
        A note to a captain reporting all is quiet on his front. 1 p.
  - Court Martial Proceedings, 1862 August-December; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    Court martial proceedings from approximately twenty military trials in the second half of 1862. Many of the trials have multiple documents associated with them.
  - Discharges, 1862 June-October; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    Discharges, many by order of General George B. McClellan and signed by Assistant Adjutant General S[eth] Williams. Most were sent to General Erasmus Darwin Keyes. 38 items.
  - General Orders, 1862 July-August; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    General orders concerning various military persons and activities. 9 items.
  - Leaves of Absence, 1862 July-December; 2 folders
    - Requests, 1862 July-October; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      Requests for a leave of absence from the Army of the Potomac, addressed to various generals. 9 items.
    - Granted Requests, 1862 July-December; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      Granted leaves of absence, many issued by General George B. McClellan, signed by Assistant Adjutant General S[eth] Williams and sent to General Erasmus Darwin Keyes. 51 items total.
  - Lists, 1862 April-December; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    Various lists of casualties, inventories, personnel, etc. Many associated with the 4th army corps. 23 items.
  - Recruiting Service, 1862 August-October; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    Papers relating to the recruiting service including special orders, lists, and nominations. 21 items.
  - Resignations, 1862 April-October; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    Resignations from officers of the Army of the Potomac, mostly due to poor health. 24 items.
  - Special Orders, 1862 June-December; 2 folders
    - Appointments/Assignments, 1862 June-December; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Special orders from the Army of the Potomac relating to assignments and appointments of individuals or small groups. Many are copies or extracts sent to Major General [Erasmus Darwin] Keyes and signed by S[eth] Williams, Assistant Adjutant General. 64 items.
    - Regulations, 1862 July-August; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      Special orders from the Army of the Potomac relating to the regulation of conduct and operations in the army. Many were issued by command of General George B. McClellan, signed by Assistant Adjutant General S[eth] Williams, and sent to General [Erasmus Darwin] Keyes. 18 items.
  - Miscellaneous, 1862; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    Miscellaneous receipts and slips of paper. 7 items.
- United States. Continental Army, 1777-1781; more than 5 folders
  This file consists of various official documents of the Continental Army. Researchers should note that the Andre De Coppet Collection contains many other materials related to the Continental Army and Revolutionary War, which are filed under the names of specific authors and correspondents.
  - Convention Prisoners, 1781 June 16; 1 item (Folder 1)
    DS, Lancaster, Pennsylvania. Signed by 42 British officers of General John Burgoyne's army, taken as prisoners of the United States [known as Convention prisoners], agreeing to conditions of parole. 2 pp.
  - Muster Rolls, 1777-1779; 2 folders (Folder 2-3)
    Muster rolls of various New England companies, signed by captains, with multiple under Colonels Samuel B. Webb, Edward Wigglesworth, and Henry Sherburne. Two are housed in the Box 46 (oversize) and signed by George Clinton. 37 items.
  - Pay Rolls, 1777 -1779; 5 folders (Folder 4-8)
    Pay rolls of various New England companies, signed by captains, with numerous under Colonels Samuel B. Webb and Henry Sherburne. 97 items, foldered by year with one in Box 46 (oversize).
  - Ration Receipts, 1777-1779; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    Eleven bills for rations for regiments and individuals, receipted, from Massachusetts and Rhode Island. With an ADS from Ebenezer Hancock [Deputy Paymaster General] to Benjamin Stelle referring to ration abstracts. 12 items.
  - Warrants, 1777-1779; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    Warrants for the payment of various companies and officers. Each is signed by one of three generals: William Heath, Horatio Gates, or John Sullivan. 25 items.
- United States. Continental Congress, 1777-1785; portions of 2 boxes
  - United States. Continental Congress, 1777 December 19; 1 item
    Resolve that no British Prisoners be released until all accounts are settled for provisioning and clothing them. Passed in response to British Commander in Chief Sir William Howe's requirements that the Colonists provision the American prisoners. 2 pp.
  - United States. Continental Congress, 1778 February 3; 1 item
    Resolve requiring every officer commissioned by Congress to swear an oath of allegiance to the United States and declare no allegiance to George III. 1 p.
  - United States. Continental Congress, 1778 February 5; 1 item
    Resolve requiring commanding officers to furnish the Regimental Paymaster with detailed pay rolls at the end of every month; also calling for the hiring of a number of auditors to oversee the accounts. 2 pp.
  - United States. Continental Congress, 1783-1784; 1 item
    Consists of a November 1, 1783 report faulting the states for failing to keep up their representation in Congress, followed by an April 19, 1784 resolution to increase the representation of each state from two to three delegates. Signed Charles Thomson, Secretary. 2 pp.
  - United States. Continental Congress, 1785 June 7; 1 item
    Resolve to provide for officers who have been disabled in the service of the United States. Signed Charles Thomson, Secretary. 2 pp.
  - United States. Continental Congress, 1785 October 16; 1 item
    An Ordinance for the Establishment of the Mint of the United States of America; and for Regulating the Value and Alloy of Coi0. Signed Charles Thomson, Secretary. 1 p.
  - Resolution, 1781 April 5; 1 item (Folder 11)
    Copy of a handwritten resolution congratulating General Rochambeau and Admiral Des Touches on the Chesapeake expedition of the French fleet. Signed by Secretary Charles Thomson. With a French translation. 3 pp total.
- Van Buren, Martin (1782-1862), 1823 May 16-1853 June 9; 1 folder
  Served as eight President of the United States from 1837-1841.
  - Letters, 1823 May 16-1853 June 9; portion of 1 folder
    - Cass, Lewis, 1836 March 9; 1 item (Folder 15)
      ALS. Discussing a Major Spilman of North Carolina, who has requested some favor. 2 pp.
    - Cutts, Richard, 1830 September 13; 1 item (Folder 15)
      ALS. Introducing the bearer, William Darlington, who is deaf & dumb but of great intelligence and can help Cutts complete a job before the next meeting of Congress. 2 pp.
    - Dodge, Henry, 1834 September 8; 1 item (Folder 15)
      ALS, Lebanon Springs. Introducing Charles P. Kirkland of Utica. 2 pp.
    - Gilpin, Eliza, 1848 January 22-1853 June 9; portion of 1 folder
      - Gilpin, Eliza, 1848 January 22; 1 item (Folder 15)
        ALS, New York. Asking her to forward an enclosure to a Miss Wadsworth. 1 p.
      - Gilpin, Eliza, 1853 June 9; 1 item (Folder 15)
        ALS, Belfast. Describing his visit to Ireland and discussing future travel plans. 10 pp.
    - Silvester, Miss, 1849 March 24; 1 item (Folder 15)
      ALS, Lindenwald. About a cactus and orange tree he is sending and enclosing a letter for her to read and enjoy [not included]. 5 pp.
    - Tazewell, Littleton W, 1830 May 10; 1 item (Folder 15)
      ALS. Asking the Senate to postpone adjournment as the President [Andrew Jackson] will likely address Congress on the subject of Colonial Trade in the next few days.
    - Thompson, Smith, 1823 May 16; 1 item (Folder 15)
      ALS, Albany. Wishing him better health, saying that a promised letter about the Presidency is better suited to a discussion. 2 pp.
  - Order, 1841 February 11; 1 item (Folder 15)
    DS. Ordering the Secretary of State to affix the Seal of the United States to an order concerning a penalty incurred by the steamer Semaphone. 1 p.
- Van Ness, William Peter (1778-1826), 1819 April 21; 1 item (Folder 16)
  Friend of Aaron Burr, served as his second in the duel with Alexander Hamilton. ALS to T. W. Oliott[?]. Explaining his failure to pay a note. 1 p.
- Van Rensselaer, Killian K. (1763-1845), 1816 February 2; 1 item (Folder 17)
  ANS. Note of Van Rensselaer to the Trustees of the Albany Academy promising to pay back $100 with interest. 1 p.
- Varick, Abraham, 1776 March 28; 1 item (Folder 18)
  ALS, New York. To his brother, Richard Varick. Reporting on clothing for officers, the British being driven from Boston, and the strength of New York; sending a new pair of shoes. 2 pp.
- Varick, John, Jr., 1776 April-June 25; 1 folder
  Letters to Richard Varick, his brother.
  - Varick, John, Jr., 1776 April 1; 1 item (Folder 19)
    ALS, New York. Describing his service with the Fusiliers under Livingston and the building of fortifications at New York; saying the British evacuation from Boston has enthused the nation and left only the British fleet to be feared; mentioning rumors of the British on Bedloe's Island. 2 pp.
  - Varick, John, Jr., 1776 May 14; 1 item (Folder 19)
    ALS, New York. Describing a dispute over whether [H.B] Livingston can rightfully and successfully command two companies; saying he is flattered that Dr. Middleton has left him in charge of his house and finances while he travels to Bermuda; reporting that captured Tories have refused to take an oath; with news of friends and family. 3 pp.
  - Varick, John, Jr., 1776 June 10; 1 item (Folder 19)
    ALS, New York. Updating about the status of a dispute involving [H.B.] Livingston; expressing annoyance that the Doctor [Middleton] has not returned from the West Indies; reporting companies in New Jersey who refuse to take up arms; describing a troubling letter circulating New York; passing news of a lack of food in Bermuda. 3 pp.
  - Varick, John, Jr., 1776 June 25; 1 item (Folder 19)
    ALS, New York. Saying he has been called as part of the draft, updating on Doctor [Middleton], complaining about the allegiances of Governor [William] Tryon [with reference to the Hickey plot], giving account of a trip to Long Island to apprehend an accused man. 2 pp.
- Varick, Richard (1753-1831), 1776 October 3-1819 September 25; 1 folder
  American Revolutionary officer and politician in the New York/New Jersey region.